# ANINDHYA KUSHAGRA

in /in/anindhya-kushagra-056136226/ 7 /github.com/anindhya1/

#### **ABOUT ME**

Looking for opportunities in software (pref. AI/ML Engineering). Pursuing a masters degree in Computer Science, specializing in AI, at Rochester Institute of Technology, NY. Three years of work experience in programming, UX design and business.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Co-Founder at CatCo., Bangalore, India

Jun 2022 - May 2023

- Formulated product recipe
- Built company website, which received 50+ order requests within the first week
- Managed operations, sourced reliable suppliers and 800kg meat orders
- Played a significant role in company branding and setting strategic direction

# Research Assistant (Remote) at Exertion Games Lab, Monash University, Melbourne

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

 Researching with Christal Clashing, a PhD candidate at the Lab, on interactive play in aquatic environments

# UX Intern at Defy(YC S21), Bangalore, India UX Portfolio

Dec 2021 - Feb 2022

- · Conducted User Research on 100+ users
- Created 5 Product Requirement Documents and collaborated with backend team, resulting in a 30% increase in activation rate
- Worked on UX Design for app features to differentiate the product from its competitors
- · Worked on Branding and Marketing
- Designed a drip campaign resulting in a 12% increase in activation rate

# Programmer Analyst at Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai, India Jul 2020 - Sep 2021

- Analysed Report Program Generator codes to identify causes of data issues
- · Provided IT support to Mattel, Inc.

# Intern at Ubisoft Entertainment India Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

- Helped solve for a localization issue in a sandbox game called 'Growtopia'
- Analysed the code of 'Growtopia' and identified >50% of strings to be localized

# **Project Trainee at Tata Consultancy Services, Hyderabad, India**

May 2018 - Jun 2018

Worked on a face detection OpenCV project at 'Innovations Lab'

# Intern at Prism Cybersoft Private Limited, Mumbai, India

Dec 2017

 Worked on UI/UX design layouts for a Change Request module in Electronic Task Management System software

#### **RESEARCH AND PROJECTS**

# Personal Knowledge Management Tool

An Al-powered personal knowledge management tool, grounded in LLM systems engineering, that helps users extract, organize, and visualize insights from diverse content sources—such as articles, videos, and books—by building interconnected knowledge graphs and generating contextual insights. 

https://github.com/anindhyal/Knowledge-Management-Tool

# **Creating Generative Art through Processing using Heart Rate Sensing**

Kushagra, Anindhya, and R, Radha. *International Journal of Innovative Technology and Exploring Engineering*, vol.9, issue.5, 2020, pp. 1401-1405, doi:10.35940/ijitee.E2590.039520.

#### **Particles**

It is an extension of the HCI research project, wherein I have used a flocking algorithm and design principles such as Perlin Noise to enhance the Generative Art output. O https://github.com/anindhyal/Particle-Systems---HCI-Project

#### **EDUCATION**

Rochester Institute of Technology,

Rochester NY Aug 2023 - Current

Masters in Computer Science

SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Kattankulathur, Chennai. India

Jul 2016 - Jun 2020

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

- 83.18% ||  $7.61/10 \ CGPA$ 

#### SKILLS

**Languages:** English, Hindi, Tamil

**Programming:** Java, Python, C++, JavaScript, Processing, C, SQL, HTML, CSS **Software & Tools:** LangGraph, LangSmith, OpenAl SDKs, CrewAl, Ollama, Cursor,

OpenCV, Figma, Processing, Arduino IDE, Muse 2(BCI headband),

Mind Monitor, Unity, PostHog, Metabase, Customer.io

Certifications: IIT Bombay HCI Monsoon Course 2024 Link

The Complete Agentic Al Engineering Course (Udemy) Link

Meta, Introduction to Front-End Development Link

Introduction to Game Development, Michigan State University Link Human-Computer Interaction, Offered at Georgia Tech as 6750,

Course on Udacity

#### **EXTRACURRICULAR**

SpaceCHI 2.0 workshop, CHI 2022 and SpaceCHI 3.0 at CHI 2023	May 2022
Member of Association for Computing Machinery Special Interest Group on Computer–Human Interaction (ACM SIGCHI)	Jan 2019 - May 2020
Volunteered at NGO Samarthanam Trust for the Disabled	July 2022
Member of NGO Mindful Change	Apr 2019 - May 2020

Participated in Indian Film Projects (IFP) 2016, 50 Hour Movie Making

Competition Sep 2016